My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him.
أُجبر طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلص جسده
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
،رغم أنّي أصبحت أصغر !لا يزال عقلي عقل مُتحرٍّ عظيم
Today's case takes place in a department store at night!
تدور أحداث قضيّة اليوم في مركز تسوّق ليلاً
The empty floors after closing time...
...الطوابق الفارغة بعد وقت الإغلاق
Even under the cover of night, there is always only one truth!
!حتّى تحت غطاء الليل، الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
The Department Store Hijack.
سرقة مركز التسوق
We have you now, Yaiba!
!أنت لنا الآن يا يايبا
Send him to hell, guys!
!أرسلاه للجحيم
I, Yaiba, shall defend world peace!
!سأحمي أنا، يايبا، سلام الأرض
Yaiba!
!يايبا
Take care of those jerks!
!اقض على هؤلاء الأشرار
Use your kick!
!استعمل ركلتك
Yaiba Kick!
!ركلة يايبا
I'm in high school. So what am I doing watching this drivel?
أنا طالبٌ في الثانوية، فلمَ أشاهد مسرحيات كهذه؟
Don't you like Yaiba, Conan-kun?
لا تُحب يايبا يا كونان-كن؟
I love it! Go, Yaiba!
!أ-أحبه كثيراً! انطلق يا يايبا
Okay, say cheese!
!حسنٌ، سنلتقط الصورة
Talk about fun!
!يا للتسلية
Thank you for shopping with us today.
شكراً على تسوّقكم معنا اليوم
Thank you. We look forward to seeing you again.
شكراً جزيلاً، نتمنى رؤيتكم مُجدداً
Bye!
!إلى اللقاء
Yaiba! Yaiba! He fights for justice! Yaiba!
!يايبا! يايبا! يقاتل للعدالة! يايبا
It's gone!
!ا-اختفى
Yaiba's autograph is gone!
!توقيع يايبا
You lost it?!
فقدته؟
I was going to treasure it for my entire life, too...
...كنتُ سأكتنزه لبقيّة حياتي أيضاً
Hold on a minute.
...انتظر لحظة
When we took the picture with Yaiba, I seem to remember...
...بعد التقاطنا الصورة مع يايبا، وفقما أذكر
Let me see the picture, Ayumi-chan.
أريني الصورة يا أيومي-تشان
Okay...
حسناً
Here you go!
هاك
I seem to recall Genta saying that he was hungry when we took this...
...قال غينتا أنّه جائع عندما التقطناها على ما أذكر
Yeah! I bought a hot dog and then--
...أجل، اشتريتُ هوت دوغ ثمّ
It's at that shop! I'm going to get it!
!إنّه ذاك المحلّ! سأذهب لأخذه
But the place is closed by now. I say leave it for tomorrow.
لكنّ المركز مغلقٌ الآن، يجدر بك تأجيله للغد
Do whatever you want! I'm going to go get it!
!افعل ما تشاء، أنا سأذهب لأخذه
Genta-kun!
!غينتا-كن
Wait!
!انتظر
Hey!
!لحظة
Whoops. My deductive skills are to blame for this.
تبّاً، ارتدّ تحليلي عليّ
Please hurry! The security system is going to activate in 10 minutes!
بسرعة من فضلكما، سيتفعّل نظام الأمان بعد 10 دقائق
Genta-kun. That door's going to lock when the security system activates!
غينتا-كن، سيُقفل الباب عندما يتفعّل نظام الأمان
I can get it in less than 10 minutes!
!يمكنني أخذه في أقلّ من 10 دقائق
See you tomorrow!
إلى اللقاء
Now!
!الآن
Wait!
!انتظر
Hey! Stop!
!أنتم! توقفوا
Ugh!
!يا إلهي
Yikes!
...تبّاً
Here it is!
!ها هو
Yes! My treasure's safe!
!حمداً لله! وجدت كنزي
All thanks to Conan-kun's great detective skills!
هذا بفضل تحليل كونان-كن الدقيق
No, this was nothing at all...
كلا، لم يكن شيئاً يُذكر
We better hurry before the security system activates!
!علينا الإسراع وإلّا سيتفعّل نظام الأمان
No!
!كلا
What now?!
ما-ما العمل الآن؟
If we go to the security guards' office inside the building
إن ذهبنا لمكتب الحرّاس في المبنى
and explain the situation, I'm sure they'll let us out!
وشرحنا الظروف فسيتركوننا نخرج حتماً
Really?!
حقاً؟
Let's see here...
...حسنٌ، مكتب الحرّاس
Security Office! Floor B2!
!إنّه في الطابق السفليّ الثاني
Masked Yaib--
...يايبا المقنـ
The jewelry store's on the 6th floor, right?
متجر المجوهرات في الطابق السادس، صحيح؟
Yeah. And there are antiques in the convention hall on the 7th floor.
أجل، وتوجد تحف أثرية في قاعة المؤتمرات في الطابق السابع
It's the elevator lady--
...إنّها مضيفة المصـ
Excellent. We have until morning to take whatever we want.
حسنٌ، لدينا حتّى الصباح لأخذ كل ما نشتهيه
It's a gang of thieves!
!عـ-عصابة لصوص
We're in big trouble if they find us!
!سنكون في ورطة لو أمسكوا بنا
They'll kill us! Let's get outta here!
!سيقتلوننا! لنهرب بسرعة
But what about the elevator lady and those other people?!
لكن ماذا عن مضيفة المصعد والحراس؟
For now, let's stay hidden and contact the police! Okay?
لنختبئ حالياً بأيّ حال ونتصل بالشرطة، واضح؟
Yeah!
أجل
Huh?! There's no dial tone!
ماذا؟ لا رنين خطّ؟
The cord's been cut!
!السلك مقطوع
This one too!
!هذا أيضاً
They've all been cut!
كلّها مقطوعة
Let's use this phone!
!لنستعمل هذا الهاتف
Nope. It doesn't work.
لا جدوى، لا حرارة
The phones must be down because of the security system!
لا بدّ أنّ الهواتف لا تعمل بسبب نظام الأمان
So nobody's going to come to rescue us?!
لن يأتي أحد لنجدتنا إذاً؟
I want to eat a ton of eel lunches before I get killed!
أريد أكل الكثير من سمك الأنقليس قبل أن أُقتل
It's too early to give up just yet!
!من المبكر الاستسلام
Please notice!
!لاحظوه رجاءً
Help!
!النجدة
Up here!
!انظروا هنا
It didn't work...
لا جدوى
Genta-kun!
غينتا-كن
Knock it off!
!توقف
The robbers will hear us!
!سيسمعنا اللصوص
Darn, it won't break!
تبّاً، لا تُكسر أبداً
Give it up! The windows here are made of especially thick glass!
لن تنجح، النوافذ هنا من زجاج سميك خاص
Alright! In that case...
...حسناً، في هذه الحالة
Okay! Cut it!
حسنٌ، اقطعها
You got it!
عُلِم
Come to papa!
!تعالي
What's that?!
!ما-ما هذا؟
Security office! There's a weird sound coming from the 7th floor!
!مكتب الحراسة! يوجد صوت غريب في الطابق السابع
Roger that.
عُلِم
Hey. Use the security cameras to check out the 7th floor!
تفقد الطابق السابع باستعمال كاميرات المراقبة
I'm pooped...
...تعبت
I told you it was pointless!
!أخبرتك أنك لن تنجح
Everyone get down!
!انبطحوا جميعاً
Hey, Conan! What about the window?!
!كونان! ماذا عن النافذة؟
Oh no!
!تبّاً
It's no good! You won't make it in time!
!لا جدوى، لن تنتهي في الوقت
Nothing strange that I can see.
لا أرى شيئاً غريباً
Nothing strange?! Those were some pretty loud sounds we heard!
لا شيء غريب؟ سمعنا أصواتاً عالية
Let's go! Let's take the loot and split!
لنسرع بأخذ الغنائم ونرحل فقط
No. Let's check it out just to be safe.
كلا، علينا تفقد الأمر من باب الحيطة
Darn it, aren't there any exits around here?
تبّاً، ألا توجد مخارج هنا؟
Quiet!
!صمتاً
Someone's coming!
أحدهم قادم
Genta-kun!
!غينتا-كن
Found you, you little brats!
!ها أنتم أيّها الصغار
Oh no!
!تبّاً
Sorry I'm so late!
!آسفةٌ على التأخير
Sonoko and I got caught up in a discussion...
أطلتُ في الكلام مع سونوكو
I'll make dinner right away!
سأعدّ العشاء سريعاً
They've seen our faces! Get 'em!
!رأوا وجهينا! أمسك بهم
Everyone get on!
!اصعدوا جميعاً
Here goes!
حسنٌ
Come back here!
!ارجعوا
Security office! Do you read me?! Turn on the lights!
!مكتب الحراسة! أتسمعني؟ أضيئوا المكان
What'd you say? I didn't copy...
...ماذا قلت؟ لم نسمعك
There's a bunch of little brats in the store!
!يوجد جماعة صغار في المركز
Where'd those lousy kids go?!
أين ذهب أولئك الملاعين؟
Hey! What's going on?! Hey!
!ما الذي يجري؟! أجبني
What's going on?!
!ماذا هناك؟
The other guys in the security office know we're here!
انتبه الآخرون في مكتب الحراسة لوجودنا
They turned on the lights to catch us!
شغّلوا الأنوار للإمساك بنا
Let's get away from here!
!لنهرب من هنا بسرعة
Dad. Dad!
!أبي، أبي
What do you want?
ماذا تريدين؟
Conan-kun still hasn't come home!
!لم يعد كونان-كن بعد
How should I know where that lousy kid is?
كيف لي أن أعرف حياته؟
Why'd you wake me up?
...لمَ أيقظتني
Dad!
!أبي
What good timing!
!توقيت ممتاز
Genta! Get out! Everyone out! Hurry!
!اخرج يا غينتا! أنتما أيضاً! بسرعة
What's going on, Conan-kun?
ما الخطب يا كونان-كن؟
Oh! They almost had us trapped!
هكذا إذاً، كادوا يحتجزوننا
That was close!
كان ذلك وشيكاً
Thanks, Conan-kun!
شكراً لك يا كونان-كن
Save that for after we get out of this place!
احتفظي بكلامك لحين خروجنا
I thought Conan was at the department store.
ظننتُ كونان في مركز التسوّق
Didn't he go with his friends to see some kids' show?
قال أنّه سيذهب مع بقية الصبية لمشاهدة عرض أطفالٍ ما
It's pitch dark outside.
الظلام حالك في الخارج
Did you try calling the store?
جرّبتِ الاتصال بمركز التسوّق؟
Where's my food, anyway?
وأين طعامي؟
Are you trying to starve me to death?!
أتنوين تجويعي للموت؟
This is Marutan Department Store.
هذا مركز تسوّق ماروتان
We are currently closed.
نحن مغلقون حالياً
Hurry! We need to get as far away from them as possible!
!بسرعة! علينا الابتعاد عنهم قدر المستطاع
Got you!
!ها أنتم
We will be open during our regular hours tomorrow, from 10 am--
سنعاود الافتتاح في ساعات عملنا ...الاعتيادية غداً من العاشرة صباحاً
See? So what do you say you make me some dinner now?
أخبرتك، ما رأيك بأن تعدّي عشائي الآن؟
Now who are you calling?
بمن ستتصلين هذه المرّة؟
Is this the Kojima household? This is Mori Ran.
أهذا منزل كوجيما؟ أنا ابنة موري
Has Genta-kun--
...هل عاد غينتا-كن
Come back here!
!انتظرا
Those voices...
...هذان الصوتان
They've been caught!
...أمسكوا بغينتا وميتسوهيكو
You stay here and hide!
ابقي هنا واختبئي
Got it?!
واضح؟
Yeah!
!أجل
Let go!
!دعني
Where are the other two?!
!أين الآخران؟
Help! I don't wanna die!
!النجدة! لا أريد الموت
Stop right there! This is the police!
!توقفوا! نحن الشرطة
We have this department store surrounded!
!مركز التسوّق هذا محاصر
There's no escape!
!لا مهرب لكم
Put your weapons down and release the children!
!ارموا أسلحتكم وأطلقوا سراح الأطفال
This way! Hurry!
!من هنا! بسرعة
Damn kids!
!تبّاً لكم
There's no police here!
!لا توجد شرطة هنا
Just those kids!
!فقط الأطفال
Damn it! They used a bunch of stupid mannequins!
!اللعنة! استعملوا هذه المجسمات
Don't let 'em get away!
!لا تدعوهم يهربوا
Is this the Yoshida residence? I'm Conan Edogawa's--
...أهذا منزل يوشيدا؟ أنا من بيت إيدوغاوا كونان
Eh? Ayumi-chan hasn't come home yet either?
ماذا؟ لم ترجع أيومي-تشان بعد أيضاً؟
I just had a call from Mitsuhiko-kun's family too...
...تلقيتُ اتصالاً من عائلة ميتسوهيكو-كن أيضاً
What is it? What's going on?
ماذا؟ ما الذي يجري؟
Get up, Genta! Do you want them to catch you?!
!انهض يا غينتا! تريدهم أن يمسكوا بك؟
Okay, okay...
...أعرف ذلك
We're trapped!
!نحن محاصرون
Over here!
!من هنا
Damn it!
!تبّاً
What is it, Conan-kun?
ما الأمر يا كونان-كن؟
Did you forget something?!
هل نسيت شيئاً؟
No, that's not it...
...كلا، ليس ذلك
I just realized something strange, but I don't know what.
...لمع أمر ما في بالي للتوّ
What could it be?!
...ما هو؟ ماذا بالضبط
Conan and his friends were kidnapped?
اُختطف كونان وأصدقاؤه؟
Yes, that's the only explanation...
أجل، هذا التفسير الوحيد
Hold on. Did any of their families receive ransom demands?
انتظري، هل تلقت عوائل بقية الأطفال طلب فدية؟
No, but...
...كلا، لكن
My guess is that they're taking their sweet time coming home.
لعلّهم يأخذون وقتهم في طريق العودة
They'll be back soon enough.
سيرجعون قريباً
I wonder...
...أتساءل عن ذلك
So how's about some dinner?
حسناً، ماذا عن العشاء الآن؟
Come on! Cook me some food already--
...أنت! يكفي وجهّزي طعامي
Is this the investigation department? Inspector Megure, please.
أهذا قسم التحرّي؟ أيمكنكم إيصالي بالمفتش ميغوري؟
Works better than I expected!
جرى الأمر أفضل مما توقعت
Jeez!
!تبّاً
Genta-kun!
!غينتا-كن
You're a real liability!
!أنت ومعدتك المُهلِكة
I couldn't help it, I'm hungry!
!ليس بيدي حيلة، كنتُ جائعاً
Come back here!
!توقفوا
Sorry to bother you at such a late hour.
نعتذر على إزعاجكم في هذا الوقت المتأخر
Well?
إذاً؟
There aren't any incidents at the moment that might involve the children,
لم تكن هناك حوادث بها أطفال للآن
but it is strange that none of them have returned home yet.
لكن من الغريب أنّه لم يعد منهم أحد
Could something have happened to them?!
هل حصل مكروه لهم؟
I've put out a bulletin.
أذعت بلاغ بحث
Don't worry, they'll turn up soon.
لا تقلقي، سنجدهم قريباً
Thanks!
!شكراً جزيلاً
Now if you'll excuse me, I'm in the middle of an important case.
أتمنى أن تعذروني الآن، فأنا في خضم قضيّة مهمة
Well, we've done all we can do.
حسنٌ، فعلنا كلّ ما بيدنا
All there is to do now is wait for any reports about them.
ما تبقى الآن هو انتظار تقارير عنهم فقط
Let's go get something to eat!
!لنذهب للأكل
Let's go...
...لنذهب
I've always wanted to do this at least once!
لطالما أردتُ القيام بهذا ولو لمرّة
Forgive us. We'll pay for this if we make it out alive.
سامحونا، سندفع الثمن إن نجونا
I wonder if we even will make it out alive...
أتساءل إن كنّا سننجو حقاً؟
Don't look so down, Genta-kun!
لا يغلبك الإحباط أيضاً يا غينتا-كن
You've had plenty to eat now, so cheer up!
!أكلتَ الكثير لذا حان الوقت لتبتهج
We're going to take care of them and get out of here!
!سنغلبهم ونخرج من هنا حتماً
In the name of the Junior Detective League!
!باسم فرقة فتيان التحرّي على المحك
In the name of...
...باسم فرقة
...the Junior Detective League...
...فتيان التحرّي
Yeah, it must be a pretty important case if they're still at it this late....
لا بدّ أنّها قضية مهمة حقاً إن كانوا لا يزالون يعملون في هذا الوقت
Are you trying to say that Conan-kun and the others aren't important?!
!أتقصد أنّ كونان-كن والبقية غير مهمين؟
No, that's not what I meant...
...كلا، لم أعن ذلك
Darn that Conan-kun...
...تبّاً لكونان ذاك
I'm missing my dinner thanks to him...
عشائي يفوتني بسببه
A gang of department store thieves?
عصابة لصوص مراكز تسوّق؟
They sneak in after the stores close and steal jewelry and electronics...
يتسللون بعد إغلاق المراكز ...ويسرقون الجواهر والالكترونيات
Could this be the important case he was talking about?
أيمكن أنّ هذه هي القضية المهمة؟
Department store?!
!مراكز تسوّق؟
It couldn't be...
...أيمكن
Calm down, Ran!
!اهدئي يا ران
Okay! Commence counterattack!
!حسنٌ! وقت الهجوم المعاكس
Now where are they hiding?!
!أين يختبئون الآن؟
Over there!
!هناك
I don't handle alcohol well...
...لا أحتمل الكحول
Me neither...
...أشعر بدوار
Mitsuhiko-kun!
!ميتسوهيكو-كن
Damn kids!
!اللعنة على أولئك الأطفال
You'll pay! We can't let you live!
!لن أسامحكم! لن تهربوا أحياءً
I'm not good with animals!
...لا أطيق الحيوانات
That's it...
...حسنٌ حسنٌ
Fetch!
!اجلبوها
We did it!
!نجحنا
Hurray for the Junior Detective League!
!مرحى لفرقة فتيان التحرّي
Wait a second!
لحظة
Aha! Now I get it!
!فهمت، هكذا إذاً
Who's there?!
!من هناك؟
It's me, elevator lady.
إنّه أنا يا مضيفة المصعد
What are you doing here, little boy?
أنت يا فتى، ماذا تفعل هنا؟
Never mind that, we're in danger-- there are some bad people here.
!بأيّ حال، نحن في خطر الأشرار في الجوار
Let's escape together.
لنهرب معاً
You can drop the act.
يمكنك إيقاف التمثيل
I know what's going on, elevator lady.
نعرف ما يجري يا مضيفة المصعد
Or should I say, the 5th member of the thief gang!
أو بالأحرى، عضو عصابة اللصوص الخامس
W-What are you talking about?
ما-ما الذي تقصده؟
It was a 5th person who activated the escalator earlier.
كان الشخص الخامس هو من فعّل الدرج المتحرك آنذاك
This person had been waiting to catch all four of us at once.
كان ينتظر للإمساك بنا الأربعة معاً
Among the remaining people in the security office,
،بين الأشخاص المتبقين في مكتب الحراسة
you were the only one who knew how many of us there were.
كنتِ الوحيدة التي تعرف عددنا
You planned in advance to get inside by getting a job as an elevator girl
خططتِ للتوغل سلفاً عبر التوظّف كمضيفة مصعد
so that you could scout out the place.
كي يمكنك استكشاف المكان
Who in the world are you?!
!مـ-من أنت؟
Conan Edogawa. A detective.
إيدوغاوا كونان، مُتحرٍّ
Excellent deductive work, boy.
يا للاستنتاج البارع يا فتى
But it seems you didn't know that I was actually the gang's boss.
لكن يبدو أنّك لم تكتشف أنّي زعيمة العصابة
A pistol?!
!مسدّس؟
It's not fair that you have a gun!
!ليس عدلاً امتلاكك لسلاح ناري
Okay! I'll lure her onto the roof!
!حسناً، سأستدرجها للسطح
The game's over, little boy! Come on out!
!إنّها النهاية يا فتى! اكشف عن نفسك
There you are!
!ها أنت
Basketballs!
!كرات سلّة
Annoying little brat!
!صبيّ مزعج
Stop your pointless resistance!
!أوقف مقاومتك العقيمة
Go!
!انطلقي
Damn it!
!سحقاً
Let me down!
!انزلني
I did it!
فعلتُها
What in the world?
ما-ما هذا؟
These are the thieves! Take them into custody!
!إنّهم اللصوص! اعتقلوهم
I don't feel so good...
...لا أشعر على ما يرام
What a bunch of silly kids!
...هؤلاء الأطفال
You can say that again.
إنّهم معضلة حقاً
The following day, we were given an award ceremony
احتفلوا بنا في اليوم التالي
for capturing the thieves.
لقبضنا على اللصوص
We didn't have to pay
لم يكن علينا دفع تكاليف الأكل
for any of the things we ate or broke inside the store.
وبقية الأشياء التي استعملناها وحطمناها في المركز
Is that really alright?
أهذا حسن حقاً؟
Don't ask questions!
!إنّه كذلك
Chalk another one up...
...نصرٌ آخر
...for the Junior Detective League!
!لفرقة فتيان التحرّي
What was that sound?!
!ما كان ذاك الصوت؟
It came from her room!
!أتى من غرفتها
Matsumoto-sensei?!
!سينسي! سينسي
Come to think of it, we were taping it!
بالمناسبة، كنا نسجل تصويراً
What?!
!ماذا؟
The murder might be recorded on this!
!قد يكون المجرم ظاهراً في الفيلم
So that was the one who smeared her dress with blood!
!كان هو من دنّس فستانها بالدم إذاً
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The June Bride Murder Case.
جريمة قتل عروس يونيو
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Medicine capsule.
كبسولات دواء